<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emad Elsaid</title>
    <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Emad Elsaid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 21:41:47 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.emadelsaid.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find a Solution for Your Problem</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/how-to-find-a-solution-for-your-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 21:41:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/how-to-find-a-solution-for-your-problem/</guid>
      <description>Open Google.com Google your problem Open all links in the first page Read page by page until you find a solution If your problem still exists, back to number 2  For more clarification please refer to the following graph
Exercise The previous image is generated from the following DOT graph, try to find how to generate the same png image from it on your machine.
digraph google { google [label=&amp;quot;Open google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exporting a Facebook Group as a Website</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/exporting-a-facebook-group-as-a-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 22:26:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/exporting-a-facebook-group-as-a-website/</guid>
      <description>For couple of years I have been honored by administrating a large Facebook group, it has over 15K Egyptian developers, it&amp;rsquo;s been there for a while, people are posting quality content, asking and answering questions all the time, writing articles specific to Egypt and other related topics, which is a great journey to have.
Facebook for a long time turned its back on groups, the interface was buggy and slow, no new features were introduced regularly, that changed for the past year, they started addressing issues, adding minor features like filters for join requests, and major features like group analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 20:14:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/about/</guid>
      <description>An Egyptian software engineer, I do back-end most of the time, sometimes front-end for fun, I mainly work with Ruby and Go, you can find me on GitHub, Twitter or Facebook
I post to this blog some notes and ideas that may or may not be practical but it interests me and I wish other people find it interesting.
I intentionally didn&amp;rsquo;t put any commenting system to my site, but tweeting the article will mention me and this could be a start of a potential thread of discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ERB Templates as Standalone Executables</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/erb-templates-as-standalone-executables/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 21:04:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/erb-templates-as-standalone-executables/</guid>
      <description>The following is a technique that can convert ERB files (Embeded Ruby) to executable files like any other ruby/python/shell scripts, the difference is that ERB is more suitable in cases where you have some output that needs to be filled with data, like rails view files, or a text that needs to report number of files/dependencies, in this post I will try to explore this idea.
first I created a file with this content</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Legacy Code</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/working-with-legacy-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 22:02:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/working-with-legacy-code/</guid>
      <description>Legacy code is everywhere, It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if the project code is there for 20 years or 5 years, if it&amp;rsquo;s not maintainable, or if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t follow a clear architecture, if there are not tests for it, then it&amp;rsquo;s legacy.
Probably you already worked with one or more legacy project throughout your career, the following are the steps I take to deal with legacy code in my day-to-day work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects Files Flame Graph</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/projects-files-flame-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 20:42:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/projects-files-flame-graph/</guid>
      <description>Flame graphs are graphs of stack of steps over each other they define a call stack for an application over time, so an application probes your running process periodically and stores the call stack, then draw a graph out of it similar to the following:
I have a project called Dirtree it takes a set of lines in this/unix/style/path/format/to/file.ext and output interactive graph of these file paths, using this tool with git ls-files you can see the whole project structure in one HTML page as a tree, similar to that</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>جينات توازن</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/%D8%AA%D9%88%D8%A7%D8%B2%D9%86-%D8%AC%D9%8A%D9%86%D9%8A/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 23:01:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/%D8%AA%D9%88%D8%A7%D8%B2%D9%86-%D8%AC%D9%8A%D9%86%D9%8A/</guid>
      <description>تطور البشر عبر مئات الاف السنوات، مروا بمراحل عدة كل منها نظرت لسابقتنا على انها حقبة همجية، حضارات بائدة يستحي البعض ذكرها وأخرون يمجدونها، لكن حضارتنا هي أخر ما يمكن للبشر الوصول له من توازن، تلك هي النهاية، حين اكتشفنا ان مجموع صفاتنا الجينية على الأرض هو ما يعطي مجتمعاتنا توازنها، كان قرار البشرية حينها انه يجب القضاء على اي شذوذ إحصائي، للحفاظ على السلام، على البشرية ذاتها.
اشاهد محادثة على احدي مواقع الانترنت بين شخصين مازالا يتناقشان حتي الان، بعد مئات السنوات، عن جدوي التوازن الجيني، أري تلك المحادثات بين بعض الأشخاص على الانترنت بين الحين و الأخر، حتي بعد ان قامت جميع الدول بالتوقيع على معاهدة الحفاظ على التوازن الجيني.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consistency Over Creativity</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/consistency-over-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 17:58:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/consistency-over-creativity/</guid>
      <description>Consistency is doing the same thing in the same way everytime, in software engineering it means using same design pattern to accomplish the same task no matter who is doing the task or when he&amp;rsquo;s doing it.
For example if you&amp;rsquo;re developing a new task, always looks for similar tasks that was done before, seek out the implementation, and do your new tasks in a similar way, use same directory structure, same naming convention, same patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Bleve Experience</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/golang-bleve-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 15:32:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/golang-bleve-experience/</guid>
      <description>I have a search engine for people profiles coming from wikipedia stored in my site, every person may have an english name or arabic name and also bilingual excerpt (the first 2 paragraphs about him from his wikipedia page),
so I started my full text search engine, used golang and blevesearch package, in the beginning my search results were not up to my expectation, as I was storing name + excerpt as one text,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bind Remote Server Port to Local Machine With SSH</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/bind-remote-server-port-to-local-machine-with-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 04:44:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/bind-remote-server-port-to-local-machine-with-ssh/</guid>
      <description>I have a VPS server that serves an application and a set of customer facing services like images server, analytics server and search server besides the main web server, but also I have some administrative services services like a database performace monitoring server called PgHero.
that particular server is not visible to the outside world, it&#39;s there listening on port 8003 but the firewall doesn&#39;t allow connecting to that port from the outside world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy rails application with docker compose and capistrano</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/deploy-rails-application-with-docker-compose-and-capistrano/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 17:57:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/deploy-rails-application-with-docker-compose-and-capistrano/</guid>
      <description>What do we have? In this article I will assume we have a ruby on rails application that is using a database to store some data, and capistrano for deployment and you want to deploy in on your server but instead of deploying directly on your server you want to dockerize the whole project to give it a separate environment and keep it away from your other applications.
Why do we dockerize a rails application?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integerating Jekyll and Octopress in Emacs</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/integerating-jekyll-and-octopress-into-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 21:30:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/integerating-jekyll-and-octopress-into-emacs/</guid>
      <description>I started using emacs couple weeks ago and i have to say that i&amp;rsquo;m amazed by how this editor is working, Emacs VS VIM war isn&amp;rsquo;t coming from nowhere after all.
one thing that annoys me is that i stopped blogging for a long time, if you checked the last blog post, it&amp;rsquo;s been a year since the last one.
so I had an idea, what if i made blogging more comforting for me?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Accepts_nested_attributes for polymorphic relation solution</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/rails-accepts-nested-attributes-for-polymorphic-relation-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 11:53:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/rails-accepts-nested-attributes-for-polymorphic-relation-solution/</guid>
      <description>yesterday i faced a problem with my rails application, my models was as follows
class Vehicle &amp;lt; ActiveRecord::Base MOVABLES = [:car, :bus, :plane] belongs_to :movable, polymorphic: true, dependent: :destroy, required: true, autosave: true accepts_nested_attributes_for :movable end  class Car &amp;lt; ActiveRecord::Base has_one :vehicle, dependent: :destroy, as: :movable end  class Bus &amp;lt; ActiveRecord::Base has_one :vehicle, dependent: :destroy, as: :movable end  class Plane &amp;lt; ActiveRecord::Base has_one :vehicle, dependent: :destroy, as: :movable end  so, when i try to create a Veihcle with nested attributes for the movable it complain with error &amp;ldquo;are you trying to build a polymorphic relation?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>