<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emad Elsaid</title>
    <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Emad Elsaid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 15:32:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.emadelsaid.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Bleve Experience</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/golang-bleve-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 15:32:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/golang-bleve-experience/</guid>
      <description>I have a search engine for people profiles coming from wikipedia stored in my site, every person may have an english name or arabic name and also bilingual excerpt (the first 2 paragraphs about him from his wikipedia page),
so I started my full text search engine, used golang and blevesearch package, in the beginning my search results were not up to my expectation, as I was storing name + excerpt as one text, so even if the person name is in the beginning of the text it doesn&amp;rsquo;t contribute to his order in the results, so it shows 10th or even 15th in the list of results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bind Remote Server Port to Local Machine With SSH</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/bind-remote-server-port-to-local-machine-with-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 04:44:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/bind-remote-server-port-to-local-machine-with-ssh/</guid>
      <description>I have a VPS server that serves an application and a set of customer facing services like images server, analytics server and search server besides the main web server, but also I have some administrative services services like a database performace monitoring server called PgHero.
that particular server is not visible to the outside world, it&#39;s there listening on port 8003 but the firewall doesn&#39;t allow connecting to that port from the outside world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy rails application with docker compose and capistrano</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/deploy-rails-application-with-docker-compose-and-capistrano/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 17:57:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/deploy-rails-application-with-docker-compose-and-capistrano/</guid>
      <description>What do we have? In this article I will assume we have a ruby on rails application that is using a database to store some data, and capistrano for deployment and you want to deploy in on your server but instead of deploying directly on your server you want to dockerize the whole project to give it a separate environment and keep it away from your other applications.
Why do we dockerize a rails application?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integerating Jekyll and Octopress in Emacs</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/integerating-jekyll-and-octopress-into-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 21:30:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/integerating-jekyll-and-octopress-into-emacs/</guid>
      <description>I started using emacs couple weeks ago and i have to say that i&amp;rsquo;m amazed by how this editor is working, Emacs VS VIM war isn&amp;rsquo;t coming from nowhere after all.
one thing that annoys me is that i stopped blogging for a long time, if you checked the last blog post, it&amp;rsquo;s been a year since the last one.
so I had an idea, what if i made blogging more comforting for me?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Accepts_nested_attributes for polymorphic relation solution</title>
      <link>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/rails-accepts-nested-attributes-for-polymorphic-relation-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 11:53:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.emadelsaid.com/posts/rails-accepts-nested-attributes-for-polymorphic-relation-solution/</guid>
      <description>yesterday i faced a problem with my rails application, my models was as follows
class Vehicle &amp;lt; ActiveRecord::Base MOVABLES = [:car, :bus, :plane] belongs_to :movable, polymorphic: true, dependent: :destroy, required: true, autosave: true accepts_nested_attributes_for :movable end  class Car &amp;lt; ActiveRecord::Base has_one :vehicle, dependent: :destroy, as: :movable end  class Bus &amp;lt; ActiveRecord::Base has_one :vehicle, dependent: :destroy, as: :movable end  class Plane &amp;lt; ActiveRecord::Base has_one :vehicle, dependent: :destroy, as: :movable end  so, when i try to create a Veihcle with nested attributes for the movable it complain with error &amp;ldquo;are you trying to build a polymorphic relation?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>